I'm Jessi, and this is my suitcase.
إسمي " جيسي " و هذه حقيبتي
But before I show you what I've got inside,
ولكن قبل أن اخبركم عما يوجد فيها ..
I'm going to make a very public confession,
سوف اقوم بإعتراف علني
and that is,
وهو
I'm outfit-obsessed.
أنني مهووسة بالملابس
I love finding, wearing,
انا احب ان ارتدي و أجد ملابس جديدة
and more recently,
ولاحقاً
photographing and blogging
تصوير وتدوين ونشر
a different, colorful, crazy outfit
عدة ألوان من الملابس الجنونية
for every single occasion.
من اجل مناسبة واحدة
But I don't buy anything new.
ولكن في الحقيقة انا لا أشتري أي من الملابس الجديدة
I get all my clothes secondhand
انا أحصل على ملابس قد استعملت من قبل
from flea markets and thrift stores.
من مخازن التوفير و مخازن التوزيع
Aww, thank you.
آه .. شكراً
Secondhand shopping
ان شراء الملابس المستعملة
allows me to reduce the impact
يساعدني من تقليل
my wardrobe has on the environment
الكلفة البيئية
and on my wallet.
والكلفة المادية
I get to meet all kinds of great people;
كما اني اقابل كل انواع الاشخاص الرائعين
my dollars usually go to a good cause;
وعادة نقودي تذهب الى أهداف " جيدة "
I look pretty unique;
انا أبدو " مميزة "
and it makes shopping like my own personal treasure hunt.
وعادتي تلك تجعل التسوق بالنسبة لي كمهنة صائدي الكنوز
I mean, what am I going to find today?
فهل سوف اجد شيئاً ما اليوم ؟
Is it going to be my size?
هل سيكون مقاسي ملائماً ؟
Will I like the color?
هل سيعجبني اللون ؟
Will it be under $20?
هل سيكون سعره اقل من 20 دولارا ؟
If all the answers are yes,
ان كانت كل الاجابات نعم ..
I feel as though I've won.
فسوف اشعر أنني انتصرت في ذلك اليوم
I want to get back to my suitcase
أريد ان اعود الى حقيبتي
and tell you what I packed
واخبركم مالذي وضعته فيها
for this exciting week here at TED.
لكي اقضي اسبوعي هنا في مؤتمر " تيد "
I mean, what does somebody with all these outfits bring with her?
ربما تتسائلون ماذا يمكن ان يوجد في حقيبة شخص مهوس بالملابس
So I'm going to show you exactly what I brought.
سوف اريكم ماذا احضرت ..
I brought seven pairs of underpants
لقد احضرت سبعة ازواج من الملابس الداخلية
and that's it.
فحسب
Exactly one week's worth of undies
ما يكفيني من الملابس الداخلية لمدة اسبوع
is all I put in my suitcase.
هذا كل ما وضعته في حقيبتي
I was betting that I'd be able to find
وكنت اراهن انني سأكون قادرة على ان اجد
everything else I could possible want to wear
كل شيء ارغب في ارتداءه
once I got here to Palm Springs.
ما ان اصل الى " بالم سبرينغ "
And since you don't know me
ولانكم لم تميزوني ..
as the woman walking around TED in her underwear --
بالفتاة التي تسير بملابسها الداخلية ..
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
that means I found a few things.
فهذا يعني انني وجدت شيئاً
And I'd really love to show you my week's worth of outfits right now.
واريد ان اريكم بعض الملابس الخارجية التي جعلت اسبوعي مميزاً هنا
Does that sound good?
هل يبدو هذا ممتعاً ؟
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So as I do this,
وبينما اقوم بهذا ..
I'm also going to tell you a few of the life lessons
سوف اخبركم بعض دورس الحياة
that, believe it or not, I have picked up
التي تعلمتها في مسيرتي تلك
in these adventures wearing nothing new.
من تغير ملابسي الخارجية على الداوم
So let's start with Sunday.
حسناً لنبدأ مع يوم الاحد ..
I call this "Shiny Tiger."
انا اطلق اسم " النمر المتوهج " على هذا الرداء
You do not have to spend a lot of money to look great.
فانت لا تحتاج ان تصرف مالاً كثيراً لكي تبدو رائعاً
You can almost always look phenomenal for under $50.
يمكنك ان تبدو " استثنائياً " دوما بأقل من 50 دولارا
This whole outfit, including the jacket,
فكل ملابس تلك مع السترة
cost me $55,
كلفتني 55 دولار
and it was the most expensive thing
وقد كان هذا الزي هو الاغلى
that I wore the entire week.
في هذا الاسبوع
Monday: Color is powerful.
الاثنين : للألوان قوة
It is almost physiologically impossible
ربما هو من المستحيل ان تكون
to be in a bad mood when you're wearing bright red pants.
في نفسية سيئة .. ان كنت ترتدي بنطالاً احمر
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
If you are happy,
ان كنت سعيداً ..
you are going to attract other happy people to you.
سوف تجذب اشخاصاً سعداء نحوك
Tuesday:
الثلاثاء :
Fitting in is way overrated.
وجوب الاندماج دوماً .. مبالغ فيه !
I've spent a whole lot of my life
لقد قضيت جُل حياتي
trying to be myself
وانا احاول ان " اكون " نفسي
and at the same time fit in.
وفي نفس الوقت ان " اندمج " مع محيطي
Just be who you are.
وتعلمت .. ان على الفرد ان " يكون " نفسه فحسب
If you are surrounding yourself with the right people,
وان كنت تحيط نفسك بالاشخاص المناسبين
they will not only get it,
فهم لن يتقبلوك كما انت فحسب
they will appreciate it.
بل سوف يقدروك أيضاً
Wednesday:
الاربعاء :
Embrace your inner child.
أطلق العنان للطفل في داخلك
Sometimes people tell me
بعض الناس يخبرونني ..
that I look like I'm playing dress-up,
انني أبدو عبثية في انتقاء ملابسي
or that I remind them of their seven-year-old.
وانني اذكرهم بالاطفال في السابعة من عمرهم
I like to smile
أبتسم ..
and say, "Thank you."
واقول لهم " شكراً "
Thursday:
الخميس :
Confidence is key.
الثقة مفتاح كل شيء
If you think you look good in something,
ان كنت تعتقد انك جيدٌ في امر ما ..
you almost certainly do.
فان حتما كذلك
And if you don't think you look good in something,
وان كنت تعتقد انك سيء في امر ما ..
you're also probably right.
فربما انت مصيب في ذلك
I grew up with a mom who taught me this day-in and day-out.
لقد ربتني والدتي على هذا المبدأ يوما بعد يوم
But it wasn't until I turned 30
ولكني لم اعيه جيداً ..
that I really got what this meant.
حتى تجاوزت الثلاثين من العمر
And I'm going to break it down for you for just a second.
وهو ينسحب على الكثير من الامور .. كما سترون ..
If you believe you're a beautiful person
فان كنت تظن ان شخص جميل ..
inside and out,
من الداخل والخارج ..
there is no look that you can't pull off.
فلن يوجد اي " رداء خارجي " يمكن ان يظهرك بعكس هذا
So there is no excuse for any of us here in this audience.
لذا لا يوجد اي عذر لاي شخص هنا بين الجمهور بان يفكر بعكس هذا
We should be able to rock anything we want to rock.
علينا ان نبدو رائعين في كل شيء نريده
Thank you.
شكراً
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Friday: A universal truth -- five words for you:
الجمعة : حقيقة عالمية .. خمس كلمات فحسب
Gold sequins go with everything.
اللون الذهبي يتماشى مع كل شيء
And finally, Saturday:
وأخيراً السبت :
Developing your own unique personal style
طور نمط ملابس خاص بك
is a really great way to tell the world something about you
انها طريقة رائعة لكي تعبر عن نفسك لهذا العالم
without having to say a word.
بدون ان تقول اي كلمة ..
It's been proven to me time and time again
وقد أُثبت لي صحة هذا على الدوام
as people have walked up to me this week
خاصة في هذا الاسبوع حين التقيت بأشخاص كثر
simply because of what I'm wearing,
فقط بسبب " مظهري الخارجي "
and we've had great conversations.
ولقد حظيت بمحادثات رائعة ..
So obviously this is not all going to fit
حسناً .. على ما يبدو ... لن تتسع حقيبتي
back in my tiny suitcase.
لكل هذه الملابس التي حصلت عليها ..
So before I go home to Brooklyn,
لذا قبل ان اعود الى بروكلين
I'm going to donate everything back.
سوف اقوم بالتبرع بها كلها
Because the lesson I'm trying to learn myself this week
لانني احاول ان اعلم نفسي درساً هذا الاسبوع ..
is that it's okay to let go.
وهو انه من الجيد احيانا " ترك بعض الاشياء ترحل "
I don't need to get emotionally attached to these things
لا اريد ان ارتبط عاطفياً تجاه هذه الاشياء
because around the corner,
لانه خلف الزاوية هناك ..
there is always going to be
سيكون هناك دوماً ..
another crazy, colorful,
شيء .. جنوني .. متعدد الالوان ..
shiny outfit
متوهج لامحالة
just waiting for me,
ينتظرني لحين الوصول
if I put a little love in my heart and look.
ان كنت احمل في قلبي الحب والعزيمة على البحث
Thank you very much.
شكراً جزيلاً لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكراً